(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T00:36:38.858672",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなー おにゅー！
Everyone, hi!
今日は姫森ルーナ3周年記念ということで、
Today is Himemori Luna's 3rd anniversary,
あるホロメンたちとずっとやりたいなと思ってたことするのなよー！
so I'm gonna do something I've always wanted to do with certain Holomem!
まずはハッシュタグは
First, for the hashtag,
こちらの #姫森ルーナ3周年記念 でツイートするのなよー！
please tweet with #HimemoriLuna3rdAnniversary!
ちゅーことでそろそろホロメンが来るから準備するのなー！
So the Holomem are almost here, let's get ready!
きたきたきた！
Here they are!
いやいや、活発！待て、活発すぎ！
No, no, so active! Wait, too active!
え、何？準備万端じゃん！
What? You're all prepped and ready!
やばっ
Whoa.
よく来たのなに！
Welcome!
あ、3周年おめでとう！
Ah, happy 3rd anniversary!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
だからそれ何なのだよ！
So what is that?!
いや今日はね、そのチョコルーナたんでVRホラゲーをやるのだぞー！
Today, Chocoroona-tan is gonna play a VR horror game!
え、おい大丈夫なのかお前、VRホラゲーといえば
Wait, hey, are you okay? Speaking of VR horror games...
過去を思い出すね
I remember the past...
まあそんなこともありましたけど
Well, things like that happened, but...
今日は万全の体制でね、やらせてもらうので大丈夫なのだよ！
Today we're doing this in full preparation, so it'll be fine!
なるほどね、安心してくださいっていうことですね。
I see, so you mean "don't worry."
安心してください、安心してください、みんな大丈夫だから、わかった。
Rest assured, everyone's fine, got it.
でも、ちょっとボタンちゃんいないのなよね。
But, Botan-chan isn't here, you know.
あ、ボタンちゃんですか？
Ah, Botan-chan?
うん。そうなのです。ボタンちゃんは残念だけどこれなくて。
Yeah. That's right. Unfortunately, Botan-chan couldn't make it.
でも、メッセージをもらってきたからスバルが代行します！
But we got a message, so Subaru will read it!
えっ！？ ちょっと、お便りをね
Eh?! Wait, let's read the letter...
ちょっと、お便りをね、ちょっと、一回外すのなよ！
Wait, let's take it off once!
えらい、外せてえらい！外すの。
Good job taking it off! Take it off.
ボタンちゃんがね、お便りをくれたので読みます！
Botan-chan gave us a letter, so I'll read it!
なんだたん3周年おめでとう！
Happy 3rd anniversary, Luna-tan!
今回急用で一緒に遊べなくて残念…
It's a shame I couldn't play with you due to urgent business...
なので4年目の時は
So for the 4th anniversary,
みんなでVRエアホッケーで勝負しよう！
let's all battle in VR Air Hockey!
(ボーリングででも可)
(Bowling is also fine)
これからも末永くよろしくー！
Looking forward to many more years to come!
ボタンちゃーん！
Botan-chan!
まじ？VRエアホッケーいいの？また泣かせちゃうけど大丈夫かな？
Seriously? VR air hockey is fine? I might make you cry again, is that okay?
泣かせちゃうって？
Make her cry?
ボタンちゃんエアホッケーやるとね、普段聞いたことないような叫び声をあげるのだよ！
When Botan-chan plays air hockey, she lets out screams you've never heard before!
あ、そうなのです？ボタンちゃんってこと？
Oh really? You mean Botan-chan?
そう！だからそれはまた今度やるということで、
Yeah! So we'll do that next time,
今日はね、3人で、あのファスマフォビアをプレイしようと思うなら！
and today the three of us are going to play, um, Phasmophobia!
あの伝説の！やばい！やばい！
That legendary one! It's bad, it's bad!
と思うけど、みんな！早くこれを付けるならやれ！後ろ向いて！
...but everyone, hurry up and put this on! Turn around!
わかった！OK！
Understood! OK!
いーち、にーい、さーん
1, 2, 3,
しー、しー、しー、しー
4, 4, 4, 4...
ごー、ごー、ごー、ごー、ごー、ごー、ごー、ごー
5, 5, 5, 5, 5, 5, 5, 5...
よし！
Alright!
いよいよ準備できたのな？
Is everyone ready?
えーい！行くぞー！
Yay! Let's go!
ボイス！
Voice!
これで行くぞ！それじゃ、いざ！
Let's go with this! Now then, here we go!
ファズマフォビア！ファズマ！
Phasmophobia! Phasma!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
よしゃ！みんな準備できたなら？
Alright! If everyone's ready?
レディ！できたー！
Ready! We're ready!
じゃあ、さっそくファズマフォビアやっていくのな！
Then, let's start playing Phasmophobia right away!
始まるぞ！
It's starting!
えー、じゃあ準備みんなそこ、スタンバイのところか、ボード選んで。
Umm, everyone, ready at the standby... choose the board.
おっケー！おっしたー！
Okay! Pressed!
ホワイトボード選んだら、スタンバイ押しまーす。
Once you choose the whiteboard, press standby.
して、スタンバイ！スタンバイ！
And, standby! Standby!
あ、こわ、こわ、どーい？ルーナが押せてない。
Ah, w-wait, r-ready? Luna didn't press it.
ルーナさーん、押して！人差し指や。
Luna-san, press it! Use your index finger.
あ、人差し指？
Ah, index finger?
すいません中指やってました
Sorry, I was using my middle finger.
まずは捜査確認のためひと勝負。
First, for investigation confirmation, one match.
その様子をダイジェストでお届けするのな！
We'll deliver the highlights of how it goes!
それではまずは、アイテムを持ちましょう！
Well then, first, let's carry items!
はい！
Yes!
え、何この青いやつ？
Eh, what is this blue thing?
どれ？あ、それ温度計。
Which? Ah, that's a thermometer.
じゃあ、ちょこ先生温度計ね！
Then, Choco-sensei, thermometer!
はい！
Okay!
じゃあ、ルーナこれ、机の上に置いてきて。
Then Luna, put this on top of the desk.
机の上に本？本？
Book on the desk? Book?
そう、これを置いてくる。
That's right, go put this down.
じゃあ、スバルはカメラ持って...
Then, Subaru holds the camera...
よし、行くぞー！
All right, let's go!
え、どこ入ってる？
Eh, where are we entering?
どこ入る？
Where are we entering?
怖いのだー！
It's scary!
やべえ、お化け。
Oh crap, a ghost.
スバルはまずは鍵を開けるぜ！
Subaru will unlock the door first!
あけてあけて！
Open it, open it!
おら！お邪魔するぜ！
Take that! Pardon the intrusion!
お邪魔虫！
Pardon the intrusion!
行くぞ！お邪魔します！
Let's go! Excuse us!
気をつけるぜ！
Be careful!
おら！
Take that!
おおお！
Whoa!
ここに本置いて。
Put the book here.
ここに本...
Here's the book...
あー、落としちゃったよ。
Ah, I dropped it.
あ、じゃあこっちでもいいよ。
Ah, then here is fine too.
あ、待って。場所をね、こうなっちゃうよ。
Ah, wait, the location, it's gonna be like this.
この子なんでがっかりしてんの？
Why is this kid disappointed?
ルーナこっちだ！EMF持ってこい！
Luna over here! Bring the EMF!
あ、こっち来て。
Ah, come over here.
青いよ？青いよ？
It's blue? It's blue?
青い、はい。
Blue, yes.
明るくしたから大丈夫ですよ。
It's bright so it's okay.
明るいよ、明るいよ。
It's bright, it's bright.
ちょこ先生どう？
Choco-sensei, how is it?
ちょこ先生、勇気がすごい！
Choco-sensei, your courage is amazing!
すごい！
Amazing!
ああ！ビックリした！
Aah! I was surprised!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
近っ！私だってさ！
Close! I mean!
なんだよ！
What is it!
嘘だろ！
No way!
嘘だってば！
I'm telling you no way!
嘘だったしか。
It was a lie after all.
一旦出直して行くぞ！
Let's regroup and go!
なんかさ、下はね、こういうねドアとかのね、ここに出たりとかする。
Like, downstairs, things like doors appear here.
ちょこ先生、しぐんだ？
Choco-sensei, you shimmered?
ここが、こういうところにに出たりとかする。こういうところとか。
Here, it appears in places like this. Places like this.
幽霊つ、ついてる？
Ghost, is it attached?
そう、なんか出たりはする。
Yeah, it does appear sometimes.
あとこっちだよ、こっちの部屋見てない。
And this way, we haven't checked this room.
ドアの、あっ！し、しもん！ああっ！うそっ！
Door, ah! Fi-fingerprint! Aah! No way!
手形ある！手形ある！
Handprint! Handprint!
指紋にチェックだ！
Check for fingerprints!
指紋...
Fingerprint...
指紋チェックっけ？
Was it fingerprint check?
おおー、ここはね、よく出る。
Ooh, it often appears here.
青いです！青いです！
It's blue! It's blue!
あ、電気が消えた！
Ah, the lights went out!
電気消えた！
The lights went out!
伊丹だらけや！
It's full of EMF!
真っ暗になってる！
It's pitch dark!
真っ暗ー！
Pitch dark!
青いよ！
It's blue!
ちょこ先生どこ？
Choco-sensei, where are you?
どこだよお前、どこにいるんだよ。ちょこ先生どこ？
Right there, where are you? Choco-sensei, where?
みんないない！
Everyone's not here!
お、どっちへ？
Oh, which way?
おっと！こっちだ！こっちだ！
Oops! This way! This way!
こっちのほうが安全だぞ！帰りまーす！
This way is safer! We're going back!
おっけー！
Okay!
指紋とあと何があったんだっけ？
What else was there besides fingerprints?
指紋しかない。
Only fingerprints.
まだ指紋だけ。
Still only fingerprints.
じゃあ次これやりに行こう！
Then let's go do this next!
アピールしてください、たつや。
Please appeal, Tatsuya.
あ、来て、来て、来て！
Ah, come, come, come!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
アピールして！
Please appeal!
誰かいいますかー？
Is anyone there?
ついた？アンサー？ついてない、これ。
Did it turn on? Answer? Not on, this.
ついてない。
Not on.
あ、今ここ3.9？下がってる？
Ah, right now it's 3.9? Going down?
下がってる。
Going down.
でも氷点下じゃない？
But isn't it freezing?
お、もっともっと下がってるね。
Oh, it's going down even more.
おお、黄色黄色！
Oh, yellow yellow!
おお、フリーズ！
Oh, freeze!
オレンジになった
It turned orange!
ルナオレンジになった
Luna turned orange!
キッチン! キッチン!
Kitchen! Kitchen!
キッチン?
Kitchen?
キッチンには…
In the kitchen...
キッチンに何?
What's in the kitchen?
何の音?
What's that sound?
なんか「はあ」みたいなやつ
Like some kind of "haa" sound.
氷点下かな?
Freezing temperatures maybe?
氷点下があった?
Was there a freezing temp?
え、なんておねむ…なんて?
Eh, what was... what?
だから指紋と氷点下にチェックがつくのね
So fingerprints and freezing get checked off.
あれい?
Huh?
なんでルナ意外に大丈夫じゃ…写真撮れ!
Why is Luna unexpectedly fine... Take a picture!
はいみんな!
Alright everyone!
せーの…しーず!
Ready... cheese!
チーズ!
Cheese!
あれ? どこどこ?
Huh? Where where?
どこいたの?
Where were you?
ルナどこいんの?
Where are you, Luna?
ルナね、キッチンじゃなくてソファーのとこにいたのよ
Luna was by the sofa, not the kitchen.
あれい?
Huh?
どこでも
Anywhere...
どこどこ?
Where where?
今キッチンに来てるよ
I'm in the kitchen now.
せーの…写ってるね! あい、チーズ!
Ready... It's showing! Alright, cheese!
チーズ!
Cheese!
ねえ、なんかビープ音鳴ってる!
Hey, some beep sound is going off!
点滅した! 点滅した! 電波ない!
It's flashing! It's flashing! No signal!
いやな来た!
Oh no, it's coming!
ああああ!
Aaaaaah!
まってまってまって…
Wait, wait, wait...
おい、誰だ、いまドア閉めたの? 誰かいるよな、ドア閉めたの? (笑)
Hey, who closed the door? Someone's here, right? (Laughs)
あれ、ルナどこいる?
Huh, where's Luna?
え、あなた?
Eh, you?
えっ?
Eh?
え、ルナ死んだ!?
Eh, did Luna die!?
死んでるー! (笑)
She's dead! (Laughs)
やだ、殺されてる! 死んでるー!
No way, she was killed! She's dead!
指紋があってよ…
There were fingerprints...
氷点下があって…スピリットボックス、なんか『はあ』みたいなのあった?
Freezing temps... did spirit box have a "haa" sound?
はあった
It did.
はあったら、ちょっと待って。えっとゴーストオーブ…あ、待ってオーブはどう?
If it did, wait. Um, ghost orb... wait, what about orbs?
オーブ? あと写真とか見よ。写真撮ってたか?
Orbs? Let's check photos too. Did we take any?
カメラねー! どんだけ殺されてきたんだよ!
Camera! How many times have you been killed!
カメラ最近もミミックで落としたし…やばいね、今言ったの確実に死ぬ、ちょっと待って
Camera recently dropped with Mimic too... That's bad, what I just said is a definite death, wait.
ミミックじゃない? ミミックじゃね?
Isn't it Mimic? Isn't it a Mimic?
これ、ミミックですね
This is a Mimic.
じゃあミミックにしとくか
Then let's set it to Mimic.
丸つけた! つけた!
Circled it! Set it!
じゃあルナ、またな! またね!
Well Luna, see ya! See you later!
おめでとう! クリア! クリア! おめでとう!
Congratulations! Clear! Clear! Congrats!
これかな? あ、ジン!
Is this it? Ah, Jinn!
ジンじゃん! ジンだって!
It's Jinn! It's a Jinn!
ほんとだ、ブレーカーをオフにすると移動速度を制限することができる
That's right, turning off the breaker limits movement speed.
ターゲット…本当ね
Target... that's right.
終わっちゃったー! 終わっちゃった、これはどうだ? もう回なのかな?
It's over! It's over, how about this? Is it another round?
もう回やな! やるやるー!
Another round! Let's do it!
ルナ余裕そうなしだ。いける、なんかいける気がしてきた
Luna seems confident. We can do it, I feel like we can.
ほんと? いきます
Really? Here we go.
え、フォトカメラ、UVライト、スピリットボックス、懐中電灯、あとあれがない
Uh, photo camera, UV light, spirit box, flashlight, and we're missing...
温度計? あ、でも1あるから
Thermometer? Ah, but there's 1 so...
これ…塩で足跡やってみる。え、いいよ? 塩って…これどうやって買うんだろ?
This... let's try footsteps with salt. Salt... how do you buy this?
ストアで買って、これだ。塩、塩あった。塩購入。だから…
Buy it at the store, this is it. Salt, salt is here. Buy salt. So...
ええ感じ? 大丈夫。塩って追加されてる。あ、あったね。
Looking good? It's fine. Salt has been added. Ah, it's there.
いいね、いけるなら。温度計も大丈夫だよね? 温度計…どれだ?
Great, if we can. Thermometer is fine too right? Thermometer... which one?
1個買っとこ。温度計入ってない? 温度計って書いてないのな。温度…あ、リストにないのか。なるほどね
Let's buy one. Not included? Doesn't say thermometer. Temp... Ah, not on the list. I see.
これだな。指先のデジタル温度計。向けた方向の室内温度を感知し…買ったらあるかも
This is it. Digital thermometer. Detects room temp in the direction pointed... Might be there if bought.
え、買いすぎちゃった? カメラだ。カメラ買うぞー! 行こう! 買おう! ゴーゴーゴーゴー!
Eh, did I buy too much? Camera. Buy a camera! Let's go! Buy it! Go go go go!
準備を整え本戦に挑むスバちょこルナ。ここからはノーカットでお届けするのら!
SubaChocoLuna get ready for the main match. Bringing it uncut from here!
待って、これ高すぎだろ！
Wait, this is way too high!
めっちゃ種類ある
There are so many types!
じゃあ皆さんそれぞれ持って下さい。
Everyone, please grab your own.
さっきと同じ感じ？ あ、でも覚えたやつ持ってばね。
Like before? Well, if we take the ones we remember...
これとこれでいいか
Should I take this and this?
これとこれ
This and this.
これ、マジで何なんだろう
What on earth is this, seriously?
持ちましたー！
I got mine!
さっきと同じの持ったなら
If you brought the same as before...
あげる、じゃあスバルもこれ持つか。
Then Subaru will take this too.
あ、じゃあ 温度計も
Oh, then a thermometer too.
じゃあ温度計持てよ
Then hold the thermometer!
行くぞ！レッツゴー！
Let's go! Let's go!
びっくりした！
You startled me!
なんで投げた？ すみません
Why did you throw it? Sorry.
テンション上がっちゃってさっきの！
I got a bit too excited.
ルナのテンションが上がっちゃった
Luna's excitement went way up!
最初、言ってないんで
At first, I didn't say anything.
なんだ、怖くねえのかよ
What, it's not scary?
もう怖くねえのら
It's not scary anymore.
怖くない？ もう行けるのら
Not scary? We can go in already?
追いかけ回してくるやついるらしいぞ
Apparently there's something that chases you around.
え、もう沸騰してる？ あいつが色々らしい
Huh, already boiling? That guy is... variety.
えー！ さっきのおかげで来なかった
Whoa! Thanks to earlier, it didn't come.
パスカに、トスコに
To Pasca, to Tosco...
で、まま！ あげい！ 電気つけまくり
And, mama! Yay! Turning on all the lights!
お風呂場どこ？ 地下室の電気ってどこにある？
Where's the bathroom? Where's the basement light switch?
地下室入って右
Enter the basement and go right.
電気！電気！
Lights! Lights!
あ、EMA反応なし
Ah, no EMF response.
嘘やん ついた！ ありがとうつけてくれて
No way. It turned on! Thanks for turning it on.
スバルがつけたんだよ
Subaru turned it on!
メンタル強すぎるやろ どうなってんねん
Your mental is too strong, how does that work?!
じゃあ、ルナはほうきタッチします
Then Luna will touch the broom.
サイン返してくれるかな
Will it sign back for me?
あれ セーフボンマイト落としてどっかやっちゃった
Huh? I dropped the smudge stick and lost it somewhere.
なんでやねん！ 何が？ あった
Why?! What? Oh, it's here.
ねえねえ シモ落とした？
Hey hey, did you drop the Shimo?
ちがっ、違う
No, wait!
何やってるの？ 体やばい
What are you doing? My body's in trouble.
え？
Eh?
あ、でもまだ全然大丈夫です、ルナは
Ah, but Luna is still totally fine.
ルナ全然平気なのらね
Luna is totally fine.
またほうき落としているやついるじゃん 大丈夫？
Someone dropped their broom again. Are you okay?
誰がほうき落としたの？ ルナじゃないの え？ 電気つけた？
Who dropped the broom? Wasn't me! Eh? Did you turn on the lights?
始まるぞ！
It's starting!
消えましたね このタイミングで持って来るのはいいあのアピール用のやつ
It went out. Bringing it at this timing is a good appeal.
行くぞ！
Let's go!
あれ、今の声、スバルの声やん
Wait, was that Subaru's voice just now?
声が化け物かと思った
I thought your voice was a monster.
え？ 今の声、シュガ？
Huh? Was that Suga's voice just now?
なんか！
Something!
アピールしてください！
Please appeal!
アピールしてください！ うわあー！
Please give us a sign! Whoa!
なんかくれと思ったらこれ付いてねえのか
I thought it'd give us something, is this not turned on?
アピールしてください！
Give us a sign!
レット・オープン！ 頼む、レッツゴー！
Let's open! Please, let's go!
レッツ・アピール・タイム！
Let's appeal time!
How are you? I'm fine, thank you.
And you?
What is your name?
My name is Subaru.
Nice to meet you. まだまだ反応ねえんだな
Nice to meet you. Still no response, huh.
みんな写真撮ろうぜ 写真撮る はい
Everyone, let's take a photo. Take a photo, okay.
どこ？ じゃあリビング集合 おーけい
Where? Then living room gathering, okay.
撮れました！ ピクチャー！
Got it! Picture!
セーフティス オッケー
Safety's okay.
おっけー、ボポライティングどう？
Okay, how about the power lighting?
あのね、キッチンのほうのテーブルに置いたのだ。
Um, I put it on the kitchen table.
How are you?
How are you? Thank you. No sign.
No sign?
え？ No sign.
Eh? No sign.
お、揃った。
Oh, they're all here.
反応しないぜ。
Not reacting at all.
No sign.
No sign. 何も出てこないな。
No sign. Nothing's coming out.
音も鳴らねえ。
No sounds either.
あ、冷たくなった。
Ah, it got cold.
冷たい？
Cold?
うん。
Yeah.
カメラ持っててくるか。
Should I go grab the camera?
冷たいです。今キッチンで綺麗になったの。
It's cold. It just got cold in the kitchen.
冷凍庫、喋るか。
Should I speak in the freezer?
はーい。My name is Choco. Choco. How are you?
Hi. My name is Choco. Choco. How are you?
チョコー、チョコーチョコー。
Choco, Choco Choco.
真っ暗、見えない。
Pitch black, can't see.
How are you? Thank you.
チョコー？
Choco?
チョコー？ How are you?
Choco? How are you?
Who are you?
あ、真っ暗で見えない。
Ah, it's pitch black and I can't see.
真っ暗になっちゃった。ライト落としちゃった。
It went pitch black. I dropped the light.
ライト落とした。
Dropped the light.
何も出てこないな。
Nothing's coming out.
ここ、チョコがやりまち。
Choco was doing it here.
なん何にしようか。
What should we do?
真っ暗で何も見えないみんなどこ？
Pitch black, I can't see anything, where is everyone?
How are you?
え？
Eh?
どこ？みんなどこ？
Where? Where is everyone?
How are you?
全然活動してない。
It's not active at all.
怖い！
Scary!
カメラ設置していない。
Didn't set up the camera.
カメラ？
Camera?
なんにもない。
Nothing there.
ないな、どうしよう。
Nothing, what should we do?
どうすればいいんだ？
What should we do?
ボポにいるの？
Are you in the basement?
え、チョコ先輩どこにいるんだ？
Eh, where is Choco-senpai?
おい、ライトないから持って行けなんだよな。
Hey, since there's no light, we have to carry it.
しお。
Shio.
あ、痛っ。
Ow, ouch.
痛っ？
Ouch?
寒っ。
Cold.
てかさ、気温とかもないもんね、これ。
Also, there's no temperature or anything, right?
え、まじで何にも活動してないぞ。
Seriously, it's not active at all.
気温見るか。
Let's check the temperature.
大丈夫か、お前は。
Are you okay?
しゃがんでるやん。
You're crouching.
ええ。
Ugh.
お化け痛くなってきたな。
The ghost is starting to act up.
痛い、でもどうしよう、何も反応しない。
Ouch, but what should I do, it's not reacting at all.
Hey.
How are you?
Fine, fine, fine, fine.
あなた、大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちょっときもち、なんか聞いてみるのね。
Let's ask how it's feeling.
塩置いた？
Did you put down salt?
いいね。
Nice.
何にも出てこん。後半に固まりかけてくるタイプよ。
Nothing's coming out. It's the type that clumps up in the second half.
おばら？
Obara?
塩、とりあえず振りまくってるか。
Should I just scatter salt everywhere for now?
悪霊退散！
Ghost busters!
塩ってどうだ？挟むんだ？
How's the salt? Do you trap it?
やばい、クエストのバッテリーがないって言われて持ってます。
Oh no, it says the quest battery is dead, I'm holding it.
でも塩もふまれてないもんなぁ。
But the salt hasn't even been stepped on, you know.
なんだこいつ、意外にもスバルだってが大声でバーベキュー乱すからさ、ビビってんのかも。
What's with this guy? Surprisingly Subaru is yelling and disrupting the BBQ, so maybe it's scared.
声出せよ！塩もないしな。
Raise your voice! And there's no salt.
音も鳴らないな。
No sounds either.
え、何なんだこいつ。え？なんなんだ？
Eh, what is this guy? Eh? What is it?
一体何ができる？
What on earth can it do?
え？
Eh?
車がそっちにいるということではないですか！
Doesn't that mean the car is over there!
どこ？
Where?
待って、声聞こえる。
Wait, I hear a voice.
声が！
A voice!
声が聞こえる！
I hear a voice!
うぉって聞こえる。
I hear "woah".
えっ、スバル！えっ、何？
Eh, Subaru! Eh, what?
え、スバル？
Eh, Subaru?
やばい、処刑タイムきてる！
Oh no, execution time is coming!
逃げろ！
Run!
あー！助けて！やばい！
Ah! Help! Oh no!
スバル？待って、どこ？殺されちゃったって！
Subaru? Wait, where? She got killed!
スバル！やばい！やばい！
Subaru! Oh no! Oh no!
どうすればいいの？逃げろ！
What should I do? Run!
逃げる？
Run?
逃げろ！
Run!
やばい、開けられない！
Oh no, I can't open it!
開けて！
Open it!
死んでる！開けられた！
It's dead! It was opened!
おい、開いた、開いた、みんな！あのドア壊れてるんだけど。
Hey, it opened, it opened, everyone! That door is broken though.
あの、あの...
Um, um...
開けました
It opened!
壊されちまったよ
It got smashed up!
あれ？
Huh?
シューター死んだ？
Shooter died?
死んだ？
Died?
ドア、ドア！
Door, door!
あ、の、ドア壊されてますけど。
Ah, um, the door's broken.
壊れちゃった。
It got broken.
ほら壊れとりやしないか。
Look, isn't it broken?
はっ！
Ha!
やばい、シューター死んじゃった。
Oh no, Shooter died.
いったものになっちゃった。
It became something that went inside...
声聞こえた。
I heard a voice.
みんな頑張れ！
Everyone, do your best!
スバルの片手を取ってくれ。
Take Subaru's one hand.
ってことは、その個が
That means, that individual...
なんだ？声聞こえて
What? Hearing a voice...
スピリットボっくすってこと？
Does that mean Spirit Box?
スピリットボックス。
Spirit Box.
みんな！ここ見てここ見て。看板見て看板。
Everyone! Look here, look here. Look at the sign, look at the sign.
看板？
Sign?
この写真見て、写真の、ここのチェックマーク。
Look at this photo, the photo's check mark right here.
チェックマーク？
A check mark?
どれ？左下？
Which one? Bottom left?
そう。
That's right.
なんかこれ、ま、え？
Wait, what is this, um?
待って待って！
Wait, wait!
これおばけなのかな？
Is this a ghost?
え？どれ？
Huh? Which one?
えと、コルクボードの左下。
Um, the bottom left of the corkboard.
左下？
Bottom left?
この白いやつ？
This white thing?
お？かな？
Oh? Is that it?
ここボボがEMPリーダーで超常現象の形跡を発見したんじゃないですか。
Didn't Bobo find the trace of supernatural phenomena with the EMF reader here?
チェックマークってことは、
A check mark means...
このEMPレベル5ってこと？
Does this mean EMF Level 5?
5になったってことやね。
That means it went to 5.
これとスピリットボックスチェックじゃないか？チェックやね。
And this and the Spirit Box check, right? It's a check.
あと、
Also...
ゴーストによる超常現象を目的。
Objective: supernatural phenomenon caused by a ghost.
これは、うーん、氷点下しもん、温度違う、ゴーストオブプロジェクター？
This is, um, freezing temp... wait, temperature is different. Ghost Orb, D.O.T.S. projector?
あ、プロジェクター当てないわ。
Ah, D.O.T.S. projector doesn't hit.
えー。
Eh...
なんだ？
What is it?
ってことは、
That means...
スピリットかレイスかツインズってこと？
It's either Spirit, Wraith, or Twins?
じゃない？
Right?
ってどれ？
Then which one?
そうだね。一体どれだ？
That's right. Which one could it be?
ぐりにく。
Grinic? (Gleaming / tricky)
え、待って、じゃあ他の、お
Eh, wait, then other... oh
ゴーストライティングがあったらスピリット。
If there's Ghost Writing, it's a Spirit.
ゴーストライティングなかった？
Wasn't there Ghost Writing?
ってことはスピリットじゃなくて、
That means not a Spirit, and...
うん、あと何だっけ？
Yeah, what else was there?
レイスとツインズ。
Wraith and Twins.
レイス、レイスとツインズ、レイスとツインズ。
Wraith, Wraith and Twins, Wraith and Twins.
レイスがあとプロジェクターがあったらいくって、プロジェクター当たらないな。
Wraith plus projector if available, but projector isn't hitting.
で、ツインズが氷点下の温度やね。
And Twins is freezing temperatures.
氷点下にはなってない？
Hasn't it reached freezing?
や
Nope.
でも
But...
どうだった？
How was it?
はい。
Yes.
温度を測りに行こ。
Let's go measure the temperature.
温度を測りに行く？
Go measure the temperature?
もうみんな30パーだから気をつけてな。
Everyone's already at 30%, so be careful.
これが最後のチャンス。
This is our last chance.
え、温度け持ってる？
Eh, do you have a thermometer?
温度けはリビングの
The thermometer is in the living...
あの、あそこに置いてある。あ、それもそうだな。
Um, placed over there. Ah, that's right too.
あ、これもやで。
Ah, this one too.
うなたん、うなたんもちな。
Unatan, Unatan hold it too.
せっかくや
Since we have the chance
はい。
Here.
頑張れー。
Do your best!
頑張れんまった。
Do your best, Unatan.
はい。
Yes.
行きます。2.5、3.3。
Let's go. 2.5, 3.3.
はい、もうついてるよ。
Ah, it's already on.
にいなちままで見守っていてくれ。
Niinachima, please watch over us.
てかあの扉開けられるのかしら。
I wonder if that door can be opened.
ぶっ壊れてる扉が。
The door that's smashed.
これ、入れる？
Can we enter this?
あ、あ、あ、閉まった閉まった。
Ah, ah, ah, it shut, it shut.
鳴ってるぞ。
It's ringing.
あ、開かない。
Ah, it won't open.
あ、開かん。
ちょっと待って。
Hold on.
ね、ちょこ開けるよ。
Hey, Choco is going to open it.
ありがと。
Thank you.
はい。
Yes.
え、なんかめっちゃ鳴ってるよ！
Eh, it's ringing like crazy!
めっちゃ鳴ってねえ。
It's ringing a lot.
がんばれ！
Do your best!
と、ライトとランプ。
Light and lamp.
こわいよー！
It's scary!
見えないよー！
I can't see!
ライトくれ！
Give me a light!
温度どう？
How's the temperature?
どんどん抜く。
It's dropping.
うなたん、こちは？
Unatan, how about here?
3.0。
3.0.
1.5。
1.5.
4.2。
4.2.
まだそうなりません。
Not yet.
ね、スバちゃんさ、下たとこは？
Hey, Subaru-chan, what about the downstairs?
しゅば、どこで知ったの？
Shuba, where did you find it?
このね、車のガレージ。
This, uh, car garage.
しゅ、しゅぺるん。
Shu-, Shuperun?
しゅぺるん。
Shu-, Shuperun.
今の音はうなたん。
That sound just now was Unatan.
1.8、4.2、奥まで入ってもいいですか？
1.8, 4.2, can we go further inside?
6.1。
6.1.
3.0。
3.0.
がんばれ！
Do your best!
4.3。
4.3.
まだそうなりません。
Not yet.
声聞こえるんですけど。
But I can hear a voice.
やばいすけど。
It's dangerous, though.
いたものろ。
It went inside...
やばい、気温がやばい。
Oh no, the temperature is crazy.
すごいことになってる。
Something crazy is happening.
見えない。
Hey, I can't see.
やばいやばい。
Oh no, oh no.
きょう！
Aah!
あ、足音だ！
Ah, footsteps!
足音聞こえました！
I heard footsteps!
きゃあ！
Aah!
きゃああ！
Aaaaaah!
やばい！
Oh no!
いやあ！
Aah!
あ！
やめて！
Stop it!
死んじゃった！
I died!
やばいって！
This is bad!
強っ！
So strong!
死んだ？
Did I die?
赤って？
Red?
やったー！
Yay!
シロミーね。
Shiromy, huh.
いたいいたいいたい！
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
頑張れちよこ、片手を取れ！
Hang in there Choco, take one hand!
えっ、てことは何だ？ってことは何だ？
Eh, what does that mean? What is this?
逃げ出がって！
It ran away!
待って待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
戦えるものがないんだって！
There's nothing we can fight with!
あとな何？
What else?
え？これ何だ？
Eh? What is this?
あとそしたら、これは？あと何だ？低温化がなかったからレイスってこと？
And then, what about this? What else? There was no freezing, so a Wraith?
低温がなかったから、レイスってこと？
Since there was no freezing, a Wraith?
低温何火にはならなかったね。うん。
There were no freezing temps, right? Yeah.
てことはレイスじゃないですか？
So isn't it a Wraith?
やだー！えっ、レイスだよね？
No way! Eh, it's a Wraith right?
よいしょ。
Here we go.
帰ってこれなかった。
We couldn't make it back.
しかも、あ、そこ天才手話1人で逃げ帰った。ごめんね、二人とも。
And what's more, Subaru ran back alone. Sorry, you two.
あいつ許さねえよ。あ、でもスバルものってるやん。
I'll never forgive her. Ah, but Subaru is on it too.
なんやねん！なんでやねん、置いてくから。お前は帰るよ。
What the heck! Why'd you leave us behind? I'm going home.
ボクの、当たり！
I got it right!
雷獣？
Raiju?
なんか雷獣って…。
What's a Raiju...
なんか新しいのでてきたんだけど。
Some new thing came out.
何これ？アンロックしたぞ！
What is this? It unlocked!
アンロック？人気だ！
Unlocked? Popular!
雷獣って初めてだったね。
It was my first time seeing a Raiju.
難しい！難しいねこれ！
Difficult! This is so hard!
雷獣？何が？
Raiju? What is?
雷獣って何だって？何だったんだ？
What's a Raiju? What was it?
なんだったんだ？
What was it?
雷獣とは19番や。
Raiju is number 19.
プロジェクターとオーブとレベル5
Projector, orb, and level 5.
稲妻の、雷鳴のっててたよね？
Lightning, thunder was mentioned, right?
ってたな。あ、そういうこと？
It was. Ah, is that it?
普段はおとなしいけど力を蓄えれると強くなるから、最初全然会えなかったんだ。
It's usually calm, but gets stronger when it stores power, so we couldn't meet it at first.
なるほどね！
I see!
雷獣は電気、電子機器を常に誤作動させている。えっ！
A Raiju constantly malfunctions electronic devices. Eh!
ってことは、さっきのぴっぴっぴっぴっぴとかやな。あれか！
That means, those 'beep beep' sounds earlier. That was it!
なるほどな！全然気づかなかったぜ。
I see! I didn't notice at all.
でも雷獣だと、ちょこせん何か大してなさそうだったね。
But with a Raiju, Choco-sen didn't seem to mind much.
行きそうだ。
Seems like it.
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
お疲れ様！
Good job!
動悸が！
My heart is pounding!
お疲れ様でした！よかったよかった。
Good work! Glad it went well.
おとなのだよー！大人なのだー！
We're adults! We're adults!
はー、ちょっと、よちまったのらに。
Phew, I got a bit dizzy.
大丈夫か、大丈夫か！いやまだまだね、やりたいことあるのらに。
Are you okay? Hey, there's still things we want to do, nora.
まだまだあるの！
There's still more!
なかなか頑張ってて草。
You guys worked pretty hard, lol.
いや、ほんとにめちゃめちゃ頑張ってた！
Seriously, we worked super hard!
なんかさ、いつもライブとかではさ、一緒に歌っているけどさ。
You know, we always sing together at lives and stuff, but...
もっとね、距離感が近い、カラオケがしたいの！
We want to do karaoke with a closer sense of distance!
距離感が近いて、距離感近いでしょう、このメンバーを目の前にしてカラオケ…カラオケしたいじゃん、ガチで！
Closer distance? Our distance is close with these members right in front of us... We want to do karaoke, seriously!
だから今日のためにね、なんとルーナの後ろにカラオケルームなのらをね、作ってもらったのね！
So for today, they built a karaoke room right behind Luna!
なに！？何、三色！いくなら、みんな行くなら！
What?! What, tricolor! If we're going, if everyone's going!
行こう！行くぞー！
Let's go! Let's go!
わー、到着なのら！
Wow, we've arrived, nora!
すごい！見て！かわいいのら！
Amazing! Look! It's so cute, nora!
ここルナたんのね、カラオケルームなのらよ！
This is Luna-tan's karaoke room, nora!
え、これ、お菓子、お菓子！
Eh, this is candy, candy!
すごい、なんかいるじゃん！
Amazing, there's someone here!
ルナナイト持ってる！
Holding a Lunaknight!
すばがルナナイトを持ってる！
Suba is holding a Lunaknight!
やりたーい！すごい！
I wanna do it! Amazing!
あのね、カラオケセットといえばね、タンバリンとかね。
You know, speaking of karaoke sets, things like tambourines...
タッチパネルもあるしね、クッションもあるし、チータイムセットみたいなのあるじゃないですか、可愛いでしょう？
There are touch panels, cushions, and tea-time sets, aren't there? Cute, right?
え、ピアノもあるよ、ピアノも！
Eh, there's a piano too, a piano!
そう、ルナたんのピアノ！ま、でも、ここにね、ちょっとね、ピアノ置いとくとね、お部屋が狭いのでね、
Yes, Luna-tan's piano! But well, if we keep the piano here, the room gets narrow, so...
使わないから消すのだよ！
We're going to delete it since we don't use it!
え、消すの？
Eh, delete it?
消しちゃうわ。
I'll delete it.
え、どんどん便利になっていくとに！
Eh, it keeps getting more convenient!
あー！待って待って！
Ah! Wait, wait!
そんな言い方あるかお前！消えろ！
What kind of way is that to say it, you! Get lost!
びっくりするわ。
It's surprising.
おうたね、三人で歌うんだよー！
The three of us are going to sing a song!
なあみんなさ、こう、じゃあ好きなとこ座って。え、ここ？
Hey everyone, like, okay, sit wherever you like. Eh, here?
てか、後ろの、うん、後ろのこれかわいい！かわいい！
Wait, the one in the back—yeah, the one in the back is so cute! Cute!
おねむぽたんちゃんもあるから
There's also the sleepy Potan plushie.
ぽたんかー！ぽたんかー！
Potan! Potan!
ここるなたん、ここに揃ってます。
Look, Luna-tan's are all lined up here.
すごい！
Amazing!
すごいじゃん！
That's amazing!
かわいいにさ、え、ここルーナんちなの？
So cute. Eh, is this Luna's house?
そうだよ、後ろの、お庭？
That's right, the garden in the back?
お庭っち、すげえ！
Garden, that's amazing!
実は、後ろの中にカラオケルームあんの。
Actually, there's a karaoke room inside in the back.
じゃでわざわざ作りました、今日のために。
Eh, we specially made it for today.
すごい、なんかいっぱいあるよ。
Amazing, there's so much stuff.
ぽちクッションもあるんだよ！
There's also a Potan cushion!
え、かわいい！ぽっぱやん、ぽっぱやん！
Eh, cute! Poppayan, poppayan!
ぽっぱやん！ぽっぱやん！ぽっぱやん！ぽぱクッションも作りました！ぽぱクッション！
Poppayan! We also made a Popa cushion! Popa cushion!
かわいいじゃん！すげえ！ま、今日は三人でね、楽しく歌うのら！
That's so cute! Awesome! Well, today the three of us will happily sing!
みんな乗って！乗ってね！
Everyone jump in! Join in, okay?
あなた、ノリが大切だから、カラオケだからね。
You see, vibe is important, since it's karaoke.
マジで全然カラオケいかんから。
Seriously, I hardly ever go to karaoke.
はちさんにカラオケだ！いぇーい！
Hachisan, it's karaoke! Yay!
いやもうスバルはルーナイトと大とけって。
Man, Subaru will melt right in with the LuKnights.
わかった！ルナイトとね、一緒にね、歌うの？歌いたいと思いますね。
Got it! Sing together with the LuKnights? I'd like to think so.
じゃあ早速歌おうか！歌う！え、なに歌うの？
Well then, let's start singing right away! Sing! Eh, what are we singing?
まず最初、これがいいかな？ピピピピピピピピピピピ。何々々？めちゃめちゃ打ってるじゃん。
First off, would this be good? Pi pi pi pi pi. What what what? You're tapping like crazy.
はい、これ。何よ？何？これ行くぜ。
Yes, this. What is it? What? Here we go.
星をまわし 世界の真ん中で
Turning the stars, in the middle of the world,
くしゃみすれば どこかの 森で 蝶が 乱舞
if I sneeze, butterflies dance wildly in some forest.
キミが守る ドアの鍵 デタラメ 恥ずかしい 物語
The door key you protect is a messy, embarrassing story.
舐め合っても ライオンは強い
Even if we lick each other's wounds, lions are strong.
生き残りたい 生き残りたい まだ生きてたくなる
I want to survive, I want to survive, I want to keep living.
星座の導いて 今見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other now.
生き残りたい 途方に暮れて キラリ枯れ続けていく
I want to survive, at a loss, sparkling and withering away.
本気のカラダ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true body.
風はやがて 東へ向かうだろう
The wind will soon head toward the east.
高気圧 この星の 氷河を襲う
High pressure attacks the glaciers of this planet.
誘い水を 飲んだ 胸がつらい
Drinking the tempting water makes my chest ache.
遠巻きな物語 かじり合う 骨の奥まで
A distant story, biting each other down to the bone.
生き残りたい 生き残りたい まだ生きてたくなる
I want to survive, I want to survive, I want to keep living.
星座の導いて 今見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other now.
生き残りたい 途方に暮れて キラリ枯れ続けていく
I want to survive, at a loss, sparkling and withering away.
本気のカラダ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true body.
何しに生まれたの? 何しにここにいる?
What was I born for? What am I doing here?
生き残りたい 埋まらない傷 光恐れてた
I want to survive, an unfillable wound, fearing the light.
許された命が 今惹かれ合った
Lives that were forgiven are drawn to each other now.
彷徨い果てて 君のとなりで 火照り鎮めたい
Wandering to the end, I want to calm my flushed heat beside you.
本気のカラダ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true body.
生き残りたい がけっぺちでいい 君を愛している
I want to survive, even on the precipice, I love you.
目覚めた命が 今惹かれ合った
Lives that awakened are drawn to each other now.
狂気におかして 祈り 捧げるよ 君を愛している
Overcome by madness, I offer my prayer, I love you.
星座の導いて...
Guided by the constellations...
生き残りたい まだ生きてたい 君を愛している
I want to survive, I still want to live, I love you.
本気のココロ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true heart.
誘い水を 飲んだ 胸がつらい
Drinking the tempting water makes my chest ache.
遠巻きな物語 かじり合う 骨の奥まで
A distant story, biting each other down to the bone.
生き残りたい 生き残りたい まだ生きてたくなる
I want to survive, I want to survive, I want to keep living.
星座の導いて 今見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other now.
生き残りたい 途方に暮れて キラリ枯れ続けていく
I want to survive, at a loss, sparkling and withering away.
本気のカラダ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true body.
何しに生まれたの? 何しにここにいる?
What was I born for? What am I doing here?
生き残りたい 埋まらない傷 光恐れてた
I want to survive, an unfillable wound, fearing the light.
許された命が 今惹かれ合った
Lives that were forgiven are drawn to each other now.
彷徨い果てて 君のとなりで 火照り鎮めたい
Wandering to the end, I want to calm my flushed heat beside you.
本気のカラダ 見せ付けるまで 私眠らない
I won't sleep until I show you my true body.
生き残りたい がけっぺちでいい 君を愛している
I want to survive, even on the precipice, I love you.
目覚めた命が 今惹かれ合った
Lives that awakened are drawn to each other now.
狂気におかして 祈り 捧げるよ 君を愛している
Overcome by madness, I offer my prayer, I love you.
星座の導いて...
Guided by the constellations...
生き残りたい まだ生きてたい 君を愛している
I want to survive, I still want to live, I love you.
さけ！
Saket!
もっと言うの！もっと！
More forcefully! More forcefully!
やめて、見せ笑い！
Hey, let me laugh!
星を廻せ 世界のまんなかで
Let the stars spin in the middle of the world,
くしゃみすればどこかの森で蝶が乱舞
butterflies flutter in a forest somewhere.
君が守るドアのかぎ
The key to the door you guard,
デタラメ 恥ずかしい物語
a scandalous, embarrassing story.
舐め合っても ライオンは強い
Even if we bicker, lions are strong.
生き残りたい 生き残りたい
I want to survive, I want to survive...
まだ生きていたくなる
I want to live more!
星座の導きでいま 見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we met gaze.
生き残りたい 途方にくれて
I want to survive, at a loss,
キラリ枯れてゆく
shining and withering away.
本気の身体 見せつけるまで 私眠らない
Until I can show you my true body, I won't sleep.
あーや！
Ah yeah!
風はやがて東へ向かうだろう
The wind will soon head east,
高気圧 この星の氷河を襲う
high pressure attacks the glaciers of this star.
さそい水を飲んだ胸がつらい
My heart aches after drinking the enticing water.
遅い！
Too slow!
笑ってるじゃん、チョコせん！
You're laughing, Choco-sen!
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
高い！
Too high!
おーや！
Oh yeah!
えー、一人ダンスをちょっとやりたかった。
I wanted to do the solo dance a bit.
ルーナのソロダンス！
Luna's solo dance!
一人ポツンってかわいそうだったから。
I thought it'd look lonely to do it alone.
せっかくのソロがルーナなのに！
It was Luna's solo part though!
だよね、こんな感じね、今日は。
Right? Like that for today.
疲れ切ってるじゃん。
We're completely exhausted.
疲れ切ってますね。
どうでしたか、チョコせん。
How was it, Choco-sen?
いや、なんか、あんまりこうやってみんなと一緒に、こう、カラオケに行く機会がないから
Well, we don't usually get to karaoke together with everyone like this,
ちょっとドキドキしちゃった。
so I got a bit nervous.
でもさ、確かにさ、チョコせんさ、ホロライブのカラオケ企画さ、何回かあったけど出た？
But come to think of it, Hololive karaoke with Choco-sen has happened a few times, right?
出たことないな？
Not really?
お呼ばれされてないかも。
You haven't been invited?
お呼ばれ？
You haven't been invited?!
嘘でしょ！ちょっと悲しい。
No way! That's so sad!
呼ばれてない！嘘でしょ！
You weren't invited? That's awful!
なるほどね。
I see.
でもスバルもさ、出たことないからさ、本当？ガチ？出たことないからお呼びじゃない？
Subaru hasn't been to one either, so... Really?
ねえ、ルーナも出たことないから、今日事前に……
Neither has Luna, so today...
事前にね！カラオケだ！
We did it! Karaoke!
やったー！
Yeah!
３度目の正直！ルーナたちも生き残れるように頑張ろう！
Next time, Luna and everyone should survive and try hard!
がんばるぞー！オー！
Let's do our best!
またね、またね、今度一緒に遊んでほしいなよ。
And play together again, okay?
うん、遊ぼうね。
Okay, let's play.
じゃあ、次の曲入れちゃおうかな。
Then, let's put on the next song.
え、次は誰から歌うの？ねえ、次誰、誰、誰？誰歌うの？
Wait, whose turn is it next? Whose turn? Whose turn?
ルーナさん！ぴぴぴぴぴぴぴぴぴ！
Luna-san! Pipipi...
何を歌うんですか、ルーナさん？
What are you singing, Luna-san?
次は、こちらを歌いたいと思います。
Next, I'd like to sing this one.
なに？なに？なんなの？ねえねえねえ、準備して貰って。
What? What is it? Hey, hey, get ready!
何を歌うんですか？
What are you going to sing?
すばるさん。
Subaru-san.
天城越え！
Amagigoe!
すばるさん、一緒に歌ってくれるかな。
Subaru-san, will you sing this with me?
なんてそれ素敵！
Thank you so much!
ねえ、選曲どうなってるの？
Wait, what's this setlist?
私ずっとこの歌歌ってみたくてね。
I've always wanted to try singing this song.
高い声、歌わせていただきます。
I'll let you sing the high notes!
がんばって覚えました！
I learned it hard!
この日のために。
For today!
よし。
All right.
隠しきれない 移り香が
The lingering scent that cannot be hidden,
いつしかあなたに 染みついた
before I knew it, it soaked into you.
誰かに盗られる くらいなら
If it's to the point of being taken by someone,
あなたを殺していいですか
is it okay to kill you?
ねえ！高い声よ！
Right? High notes!
寝乱れて 隠れ宿 九十九折り
Scattered in sleep, hidden shelter,
浄蓮の滝 舞い上がり 揺れ墜る
the waterfall of passion rising and falling.
肩のむこうに あなた…山が燃える
Beyond your shoulders... the mountain burns!
何があっても もういいの
No matter what happens, it's fine now,
ぐるぐる燃える 火をくぐり
burning, turning the fire around.
隠しきれない 移り香が
The unhidden lingering scent
いつしかあなたに 染みついた
eventually clung to you.
誰かに盗られる くらいなら
If it's to the point of being taken by someone,
あなたを殺して いいですか
would it be alright to kill you?
寝乱れて 隠れ宿
Scattered in sleep, hidden inn,
九十九折り 浄蓮の滝
ninety-nine bends, Joren Waterfall.
いいわよ 上手だったよ
That was good! You did great!
ビブラート、ビブラート！すごい！
Vibrato, vibrato! Amazing!
ねぇねぇねぇねぇ... どこ、どこどこ？
Hey, hey, hey... where, where?
舞い上がり 揺れ堕ちる
Rising and falling,
肩のむこうに あなた...
beyond your shoulders...
山が燃える
the mountain burns.
何があっても もういいの
No matter what happens, it's fine now,
くらくら燃える 火をくぐる
passing through the dizzying burning fire,
あなたと越えたい 天城越え
I want to cross over with you, Amagi Pass.
口を開けば 別れると
If I open my mouth, we'll part ways,
刺さったままの 割れ硝子
the broken glass that remains stabbed.
ふたりで居たって 寒いけど
Even if we're together, it's cold,
嘘でも抱かれりゃ あたたかい
but if I'm held even by a lie, it's warm.
わさび沢 隠れ径
Wasabi-zawa, hidden path,
小夜時雨 寒天橋
evening shower, Kanten Bridge.
恨んでも 恨んでも 溜うらら
Resentful, resentful, yet...
あなた... 山が燃える
you... the mountain burns.
戻れなくても もういいの
Even if we can't go back, it's fine now,
くらくら燃える 地を這って
crawling on the dizzying burning ground,
あなたと越えたい 天城越え
I want to cross over with you, Amagi Pass.
すごい！ビブラートうまい！
Amazing! Your vibrato is so good!
風の群れ 天城隧道
Wind's flock, Amagi Tunnel.
恨んでも 恨んでも 溜うらら
Resentful, resentful, yet...
あなた... 山が燃える
you... the mountain burns.
戻れなくても もういいの
Even if we can't go back, it's fine now,
くらくら燃える 地を這って
crawling on the dizzying burning ground,
あなたと越えたい 天城越え
I want to cross over with you, Amagi Pass.
風の群れ 天城隧道
Wind's flock, Amagi Tunnel.
恨んでも 恨んでも 溜うらら
Resentful, resentful, yet...
あなた... 山が燃える
you... the mountain burns.
戻れなくても もういいの
Even if we can't go back, it's fine now,
くらくら燃える 地を這って
crawling on the dizzying burning ground,
あなたと越えたい 天城越え
I want to cross over with you, Amagi Pass.
うますぎる！
Too good!
ビブラートうますぎて曲止まっちゃったよ！
The vibrato was so good the song stopped!
嘘でしょ！？
No way!
終わったって！
It's over!
どうでしたか、ルナさんのすばるの甘え声は？
How was Luna and Subaru's sweet voice?
すごいビブラートが上手になってましたね。
Your vibrato got really good.
でも最初の歌い出しのクセ強すぎてどうしようかと...
But the opening was so uniquely strong we didn't know what to do...
自分で自撮りしながら自撮りしてたんですよ、一人で。
I was taking selfies while singing by myself.
ふたりの手手を見ながら自撮りしようかと。
Trying to take a selfie while looking at both our hands.
今日かわいい曲多いからちょっとネタ曲に...
There are lots of cute songs today, so we picked a joke song...
まだ始まって二曲目だよ、ルナさん！
It's only the second song, Luna!
かわいい曲を選ぶ予定だったんだよ。
We were planning to pick cute songs.
次もね、これを歌うかな。
Next, I wonder if we'll sing this one.
何を頼むの？何を頼むの？
What are you ordering? What are you ordering?
テンション高けえ人いるなぁ。
There's someone with super high tension here.
ちょっとね、走ってね、体温めようと思って。
I thought I'd run a bit to warm up my body.
次は誰と頼むんだ？
Who are you ordering with next?
次はこちらを通させていただきます。
Next, we will pass through here.
キューティーハニー
[Title: Cutie Honey]
この頃はやりの 女の子
She's a popular girl these days,
お尻の小さな 女の子
a girl with a small butt.
こっちを向いてよ ハニー
Turn this way, honey!
だってなんだか
'Cause somehow...
ちょこ先生決めてくれよ！
Choco-sensei, decide for us!
ごろごろ早起きの女の子
She's an early-riser rolling girl,
この頃流行りの 女の子
The trendy girl of the time,
お尻の小さな 女の子
A girl with a small butt,
こっちを向いてよ ハニー
Look this way, Honey!
だってなんだか だってだってなんだもん
Because, well, because, because...
お願い お願い 傷つけないで
Please, please, don't hurt me!
わたくしのハートは
My heart
チュークチュークしちゃうの
Is throbbing away!
イヤよ イヤよ イヤよ
No, no, no!
見つめちゃイヤー
I don't want you to stare!
ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
カメラに向かってハニーフラッシュってくれよ！
Give us a Honey Flash facing the camera!
今どき人気の 女の子
The popular girl nowadays,
プクっとボインの 女の子
A girl with plump cheeks,
こっちを向いてよ ハニー
Look this way, Honey!
だってなんだか だってだってなんだもん
Because, well, because, because...
お願い お願い 近寄らないで
Please, please, don't come close!
わたくしのお鼻が
My nose
ヒクヒクしちゃうの
Is twitching away!
イヤよ イヤよ イヤよ
No, no, no!
見つめちゃイヤー
I don't want you to stare!
ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
次！次！次！次！
Next! Next! Next! Next!
ハニーフラッシュ中だわ！
I'm in the middle of a Honey Flash!
あなたの歌い方よ！なんかさ、よく分からんようになるような
It's the way you sing! It gets so confusing...
プクッとボインの
Plump and busty,
チクッとヒミツの
A secret little sting,
今どき流行りの 女の子
The trendy girl of the time,
コニコのどかの 女の子
A girl with a cat-like smile,
こっちを向いてよ ハニー
Look this way, Honey!
だってなんだか だってだってなんだもん
Because, well, because, because...
お願い お願い
Please, please,
追いかけないで
Don't chase me!
わたくしのおめめが
My eyes
シクシクしちゃうの
Are tearing up!
イヤよ イヤよ イヤよ
No, no, no!
見つめちゃイヤー
I don't want you to stare!
ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
だってセクシー
Because it's sexy!
ハニーフラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
じゃんけんぽーん！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon!
セクシーだったならね！
If it was sexy, yeah!
さっきさ、途中のこの動きすごかった
That movement in the middle was amazing!
こういう腰クネクネしてさ
Wiggling your hips like this...
セクシー犬よ！
Sexy dog!
何その動き初めて見たわ、そこ先生詳しいの？
I've never seen that move. Are you an expert, Sensei?
なるほど
I see.
ここまで来てしまったか、あっという間ならね
We've come this far, in a flash!
なんかさ、どんな感じでセクシーアピール待ってるみたいな感じには
Waiting for a sexy appeal like that...
ルーナさっきからすごいよね、なんか謎のSE嫌みたいにさ
Luna, your SE has been amazing since earlier!
あなたのSEがすごいんだよ
Your SE is amazing!
だってカラオケだもん、楽しいじゃん！
It's karaoke, so it's fun!
おどるポンポコリン 作詞 さくらももこ 作曲 織田哲郎
[Title: Odoru Pompokorin]
なんでもかんでも みんな
No matter what happens, everyone
おどりを おどっているよ
Is dancing their dance!
おなかの中から ボワっと
From inside the stomach, a puff,
インチキおじさん 登場
The fake old man appears!
いつだって わすれない エジソンは えらい人
Always remember, Edison was a great man!
そんなの常識 タッタタラリラ
That's common sense, tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ
Piihyara piihyara,
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapa!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ
Piihyara piihyara,
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapa!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ
Piihyara piihyara,
おそぞがちり
My navel peeps out!
タッタタラリラ
Tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ
Piihyara piihyara,
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapa!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ
Piihyara piihyara,
おどるポンポコリン
Odoru Pompokorin!
ピヒャラ ピヒャ
Piihyara pii,
お腹がへったよ
My stomach is hungry!
おなかへった！
I'm hungry!
あの人もこの人も...
That boy, that girl, and everyone...
なんでもかんでも みんな おどりを おどっているよ
Anyone and everyone is dancing away!
おなかの中かから ボワっと インチきおじさん 登場
Suddenly from inside the belly, an impolite old man appears!
いつだって わすれない エジソンは えらいひと
I'll never forget... Edison was a great man!
そんなの じょうしき
That's common sense!
タッタタラリラ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ
Tatta tararira! Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おへそが ちちらり
Piihyara piihyara, belly button peeking out!
タッタタラリラ
Tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おなかが へったよ
Piihyara pii, my stomach is empty!
あの子も この子も みんな いそいで 歩いているよ
That girl and this girl and everyone are walking fast.
でんしばしらの かげから おわらいげにん 登場
From the shadow of the telephone pole, a laughing comedian appears!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ にんじん いらない
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, no need for carrots!
タッタタラリラ
Tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ ぶたの ブタロウ
Piihyara pii, buta no Butarou!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ エジソンは えらいひと
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, Edison was a great man!
そんなの じょうしき
That's common sense!
タッタタラリラ
Tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おへそが ちちらり
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, belly button peeking out!
タッタタラリラ
Tatta tararira!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おおへそが ちちらり
Piihyara pii, oh, your head is peeking out!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おなかが へったよ
Piihyara pii, my stomach is empty!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おなかが へったよ
Piihyara pii, my stomach is empty!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おなかが へったよ
Piihyara pii, my stomach is empty!
ピヒャラ ピヒャラ パッパパラパ ピヒャラ ピヒャラ おどるポンポコリン
Piihyara piihyara pappa parapa! Piihyara piihyara, dancing Ponpokorin!
ピヒャラ ピイ おなかが へったよ
Piihyara pii, my stomach is empty!
おなかへった！おかし食べに行このら！
I'm so hungry! Let's go eat some snacks!
ああ、楽しかった！
Oh, that was so fun!
楽しかった？
Was it fun?
めっちゃ楽しかった！
It was super fun!
みんなで歌おうつって、最初誰も歌わなくてさ。げ、ウナギ養って！
Everyone was singing along, but at first nobody was singing at all!
思い出したようにやり出した！思い出だしたように！
It finally hit me! I suddenly remembered how we did it!
さっきまで無言やったのやばい！
Up until just now, we were totally silent!
急な、急な、なんのテンションが上がってきたのらね。
Suddenly, out of nowhere, your tension went way up!
違うよ！音楽あって、やってるのかわかんない。
Who knows! We had music playing, so who knows why!
あ、なるほどね！お、ここに来てね！
I see! So you came here, huh?
あで、でもね、今日ね、一緒に歌えて楽しかった！ありがとね！
Anyway, today we sang together and it was so fun! Thank you so much!
よかった！
You're welcome!
これからもまた一緒に遊んでのらね！
We'll definitely have to hang out and sing together again!
ばいばい！またね！
Bye-bye, everyone!
え？え？「帰れ」ってこと？こと？
Huh? What? "Time to go home," what?
「帰ろう」って５０００円。
"Let's go home," 5000 yen!
じゃあクレープ食べに行ってあげるよ。
Shall we go grab some crepes?
え、なに、二人で行くの？
Huh? The two of you are going?
またね！またね！わあ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
ふたりだけで行っちゃったの。なのになのら、ちょっとみんな居なくなっちまったけど。
And so, the two of them went off, leaving me all alone...
あ！待ってよ！
Oh, wait, wait!
ま、でもこのあとルナたちからの告知があるんだな！いこうのきょう！
Wait, but after this, there's a merchandise announcement! Let's keep going!
なんで？なんで？なんで？逃げ出してるの？
Why? Why are you running away?
食べろよ！早く食えよ！
Eat up! Hurry up and eat!
今日はみんなどうだったなら？
So, how was everyone doing today?
ホラケモンもカラオケも楽しかったなら！
I hope you all had a fun time with Horakemon and Karaoke too!
さいきんホラケモンとも大親友になったと思うならね、みんな！
I think Horakemon and I became really good friends, what do you think?
ということで、ここでグッズ紹介なのだな！こちらです！
And with that, it's time to introduce our merchandise right here!
まずは！
First up is...
二つ目！
The second item!
こちら「ふきふきバスタオル」！
This is the "Wipe-Wipe Bath Towel"!
こちらはね、かんざきひろパパかきおろしのふきふきバスタオルなのだな！ルナイトとコンパパとシバノドックといしょにね、お風呂に入っている可愛いイラストなのだな！ちょっとセクシーだけど、可愛くパパにかいてもらったのだな！
It features cute illustrations by Kanzaki Hiro of Luna, a Kompira, and a Shibanodakku all relaxing together in the bath!
そして、二つ目！
And now, for the second item...
ででん！「高級クラブルーナグラス」！
Tada! The "Luxury Club Luna Glass"!
ルナたんといえば、やっぱり大富豪ということで、可愛い丸いフォルムを大人にしたお酒のグラスをグッズにしたのだな！みんなこのね、グラスを使って一緒にルナたんととお酒飲むのだな！
When you think of Luna-tan, you think of being a rich adult! So we made a classy, round-form glass for drinking alcohol into a piece of merch! We hope you'll use this glass to drink with Luna-tan!
そして、三つ目はででん！
And thirdly... tada!
こちら「ルーナイトスリッパ」！
Here we have the "Lunaite Slippers"!
みんなの
Everyone's...
スリッパ～！
Slippers~!
まあ、ルナイトというね、もうスリッパの音大好きだからね、
Well, since Lunites love the sound of slippers so much,
こちらをね、みんなに入ってもらって
I had everyone wear these,
フミフミフミフミしようかなと思って
and thought, "Let's go pitter-patter!"
ぐっすりにしたならルナイトは是非履くべし！
If you want a good sleep, Lunites should definitely wear them!
そして、全部セットには、
And then, the full set includes...
浮きハゲバスタオルのイラストと、
The illustration of the bath towel,
サボンのポストカードがついてくるのな！
and a soap postcard will come with it!
こちらは金箔の複製サインになってるので、
These feature gold-foil replicated autographs,
バスタオルはお風呂場、
so the bath towel is for the bathroom,
ポストカードは上に飾って眺めてほしいのな！
and I want you to display the postcard up high and look at it!
そして、最後はルナイト、ルナイトのお手紙を届けてきたのな！ちょっと取ってくるのな！
And finally, I brought a letter for the Lunites! I'll go grab it!
えー、じゃあみんな、ちょっと聞いてほしいのな、ルナイトの手紙を。
Well everyone, I want you to listen to Luna's letter.
ルナイトへ ♡
To the Lunites ♡
ホロライブに入ってもう3周年になりました。
It's already been 3 years since I joined Hololive.
わがまま言ったり怒ったり笑ったりルナイトたちと過ごす時間はあっという間なのなね。
The time spent with Lunites being selfish, getting angry, and laughing goes by in a flash.
毎日楽しいをありがちょ～ ♡
Thank you for everyday being fun~!
いつかの配信でお話ししたホロライブに骨を埋めるという気持ちは今も変わらねえのら。
My feeling of wanting to be buried in Hololive, which I talked about in a stream sometime ago, hasn't changed.
ルナはルナイトのために頑張り続けていくから。
Luna will keep working hard for the Lunites.
これからの活動でとってももっと好きを伝えさせてななのなね！
Let me express my love even more in future activities!
ルナより。（>o<) ♡
From Luna. (>o<) ♡
えー、恥ずかしいな。
Um, how embarrassing.
ま、とゆーことで、
Well, with that said,
これからもね、3周年目もみんな癒やしになれたらなー！
I hope I can continue to be a comfort to everyone in our 3rd year too!
またねー！
See you later!